everythingeverywhere.com 2015-12-27

# Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy

**13th November 2015**

This privacy policy explains how we collect and use your personal information. In this policy, "we" and "our" means EE Limited and it covers all the products and services operated by our three brands in the UK: EE, Orange and T-Mobile.  For older versions of our Privacy Policy, click here.

Please read this policy in conjunction with the terms and conditions of any particular service or services you are using.

By using any of our services or visiting our websites you agree to our use of your personal information as set out here.

## 1\. Your Personal Information: What We Collect

The personal information we collect about you will depend on the products and services you use and subscribe to. It includes (but isn’t limited to):

  * your name, address, telephone number, date of birth, gender and email address;

  * your debit or credit card information, information about your bank account number, sort code and other banking information, and other information required to validate your identity;

  * your account information such as how you purchased or signed up to our products and services, your billing history, the products and services you use and anything else relating your account;

  * your preferences and interests both when you tell us what they are or when we deduce them from what we know about you;

  * your demographic information (which we may acquire from third parties);

  * information you provide to us when entering prize draws or competitions or participate in surveys or consumer panels;

  * your credit rating information (which we acquire from credit reference agencies); and

  * your communications with us.

We'll also get information on how you use our products and services, such as:

  * the date, time, duration and cost of your communications including your phone location at the time these communications are made;

  * the phone numbers that you call and send messages to (and the phone numbers that you receive calls and messages from);

  * the types of websites that you visit and how you use them (such as the date, time, duration of your internet session, your IP address, and your approximate location at the time of browsing);

  * your activity on EE websites;

  * your device details (such as your hardware model, operating system version, unique device identifier (also known as IMEI) and advertising identifiers on your device);

  * your phone or device usage (including voice, messaging, web/ WAP use, application use);

  * your amount of data usage (MBs used);

  * your roaming information (such as the country you are in and the network used when making communications including dates and times); and

  * your network experience (including your location information).

If you give us personal information about another person (e.g. when they receive a service you are paying for) or allow another person to use your device, we expect you to be responsible for ensuring that they know we are using their personal information in accordance with this privacy policy and have obtained their consent to this.

We may collect information about you from other organisations including from:

  * credit reference and fraud prevention agencies;

  * data brokers;

  * our partners; and

  * business directories

**Use of your Location Information**

We need to know approximately where you are so that we can deliver mobile phone services to you. Location information (such as your Cell ID) is relayed to us and some of our partners when your phone is turned on or when you use the services. This information is also shared with the emergency services if you make an emergency call so they can respond more quickly to the call and may be used to get in touch with you on behalf of public authorities in the event of a public emergency (in accordance with law). Cell ID location information cannot usually be used to pinpoint exactly where you are. For example, it cannot usually be used to determine which particular house or shop you are in at a given time. Instead, it offers an approximate location based on your position relative to the nearest mobile phone masts. The accuracy of this information depends on how close you are to a mobile phone mast and is likely to be more accurate in urban areas compared to rural areas.

Your location information may be used to provide you with services that are linked to your location such as the reporting of network issues in particular areas.

Some location services are called active location services because you are asking us to check your location in order for the service to be provided.  Your network information (which may include the country you are in) may also be shared with and used by third parties to provide you with a particular service (e.g. a fraud management service offered by your bank). This will only be done when you have given your consent to the third party and the details of this processing as well as how to stop this information being used in this way will be explained by the third party.

There are other forms of location based services where you might agree to be located by someone else or you might want to locate someone else using the location information we generate. These services are called passive location services. We describe passive location based services offered by our partners below.

**Phone locator services**

We have put in place measures to ensure that our partners who provide you with passive location based services by using your Cell ID comply with the Industry Code of Practice for the Use of Mobile Phone Technology to Provide Passive Location Services in the UK. These include measures to verify the identity of the person wishing to use the passive location service and to ensure the ongoing consent of the person whose phone is being located. One of the key requirements of this Code is that the person who is to be located must consent to being located and regular reminders about the location service must be sent to their mobile phone so that they can opt out at any time.

**Other passive location services**

You may receive certain passive location services in circumstances where you have adjusted settings or activated certain features on your phone. For example, if your phone has 'Bluetooth' enabled, you may receive messages from third parties located nearby. If you do not wish to receive these services, we suggest you de-activate the relevant feature(s) on your phone or contact the third parties directly.

Back to top

## 2\. How We Use Your Personal Information

We use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * to verify your identity and make credit decisions about you (which may include carrying out a credit check on you).  Please see the link about our credit checking processes at the bottom of this section;

  * to confirm that your orders have been received and to process them, to validate you as a registered customer when using our services and calling our customer services;

  * for providing the relevant products and services to you, for administration of your account with us and customer services, and for billing purposes;

  * to send you certain communications (including by email and SMS) such as service announcements and administrative messages and other communications relating to our services (such as functionality changes to our website, changes to our terms and conditions and to remind you about your customer benefits). Please note that you will not be able to opt out of receiving these essential service communications; 

  * for our internal purposes such as management, research, analytics, corporate reporting, credit scoring and to improve business efficiencies;

  * to ensure security for you and our staff, and help maintain service quality (calls to our customer services may be monitored and/or recorded for authentication, security, quality and training purposes);

  * to check that your home or office or other location is covered by our network and to optimise your network coverage and our network. We will use your location information for network customer experience management and for reporting of network issues in particular areas.   _Read more about the types of location information we may collect about you_;

  * for the management of traffic;

  * to trace nuisance or malicious calls;

  * to help the emergency services;

  * to prevent and detect criminal activity, fraud and misuse of or damage to our services or network and to prosecute those responsible, to trace and recover debts, to defend our rights or property and to protect the rights and interests of our customers and users;

  * to comply with applicable laws, regulations, court orders, government and law enforcement agencies’ requests, to operate our systems properly and to protect ourselves, our users and customers and to solve any customer disputes;

  * to segment our customer base and help us develop offers, products and services to provide you with the best customer experience;

  * to market and advertise our products and services, EE Group products and services and occasionally third party products and services that may be of interest to you including third party offers, promotions, advertisements, competitions or commercial communications by telephone (mobile and landline when available), post, electronic messaging (including SMS and MMS), email or online or via applications. You may be contacted by our Group companies for these purposes. For details of how to opt out of marketing communications, please see How to access and control your personal information;

  * to recommend packages for you based on your use of our products and services e.g. if you regularly exceed your voice or data plan, we may suggest you moving to a better tariff;

  * to contact you to invite you to form part of our consumer panel or research groups about our products and services or customer satisfaction surveys (you may be contacted by third parties on our behalf);

  * to provide you with personalised services and communications as well as targeted advertising from EE on our EE website and selected partner websites. This may involve the use of cookies and other similar technologies.  Please see the link about our Cookies Policy at the bottom of this section; 

  * to enable third parties to tailor adverts which are more relevant and useful to you when you are browsing the internet or are using mobile applications. This may involve the use of cookies and other similar technologies. Personalisation may be based on various factors such as your age and gender, your device details or your inferred interests but we will not share any information with these third parties which directly identifies you. However, by interacting with or viewing an advert, you should be aware that the third party may make the assumption that you meet the targeting criteria used to display the advert.  You can opt out of targeted advertising from third parties. For more information, please visit [www.youronlinechoices.com/uk](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk). However, please note that this will not opt you out of receiving adverts altogether – it simply means that the adverts will not be targeted to you.  We may use your location if you have told us that you are interested in location based offers and services.   _Read more about the types of location information we may collect about you_;

  * to create anonymous and aggregated reports about our customers, traffic and network usage patterns. We may use information about your mobile network usage and your location for analytics purposes but we will only retain this information in an anonymised form to ensure that you cannot be identified as an individual. Please see the link about EE Analytics at the bottom of this section.

**Credit Checks**

If you or your business applies for our services, we will check your details (and if you are a business that trades as a partnership, those of your business partners) with credit reference agencies and fraud and theft prevention agencies to help us verify your identify and make credit decisions about you. We will use both credit scoring and/or automated decision making systems. These agencies will record details of any search whether or not your application succeeds.

You may also be required to disclose information about anyone else with whom you have a financial link for these checks (such as spouses, partners, family or household members) so make sure you have their agreement to disclose information about them.

If you give us false or inaccurate information which leads us to suspect fraud, we will also record this and details will be passed to the appropriate credit reference or fraud prevention agencies.

We may also give credit reference agencies details of your accounts and bills and how you manage them. This includes telling them about change of address, your account balances, what you pay us and if you miss a payment. The agencies will keep this information for 6 years. They or a fraud prevention agency might tell other organisations doing similar checks, including organisations trying to prevent or detect fraud or money laundering or trying to trace you or recover money you owe them. 

Once in a while we might run more checks with credit reference agencies and fraud prevention agencies to keep your account with us up to date.

If you don’t become an EE customer, we will continue to hold this information about you for customer enquiries and for legal purposes. It also helps in the prevention or detection of fraud.

These agencies will also use the records for statistical analysis about credit, insurance and fraud.

You can request a copy of your credit reference file by writing directly to the agencies listed below. There is a small fee for this service and the information held by each may not be the same.

  * Callcredit, Consumer Services Team, PO Box 491, Leeds, LS3 1WZ or 0870 0601414 or [www.callcredit.co.uk](http://www.callcredit.co.uk/)

  * Equifax, Credit File Advice Centre, PO Box1140, Bradford, BD1 5US or 0844 3350550 or [www.equifax.co.uk](http://www.equifax.co.uk/)

  * Experian, Consumer Help Service, PO Box 8000, Nottingham NG80 7WF or 0844 4818000 or [www.experian.co.uk](http://www.experian.co.uk/)

**Our Cookies Policy**

We use cookies, web beacons, unique identifiers and other similar technologies (collectively "cookies") to provide our services and help collect data. We do this to understand your use of our websites, emails, mobile applications and services; improve your user experience and enable personalized features and content; optimize our advertisements and marketing; and to enable third-party advertising companies to assist us in serving ads specific to your interests across the Internet. By using our website, you consent to our use of these cookies.

Different cookies are used to perform different functions. We detail below our use of cookies. You do have choices about how cookies are used.

**Our use of cookies & similar technologies**

**We use cookies that are essential**

Some cookies are essential for us to use in order to provide you with the services you have requested.  These cookies will be used to manage the delivery of any web services requested by you and if you do not accept these cookies, the services may not be so easy to access and you may not be able to receive some services that you have requested e.g. pay for goods and services or access secure areas of our websites. These cookies do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing purposes or remembering where you have been on the internet.

**We use cookies to remember your selections**

We also use cookies to remember your selections that change the way our websites behave or look e.g. the font sizes or layout you have chosen etc. These types of cookies can also be used to deliver a specific function requested by you which is not core to the usage of the website e.g. streaming a video.  Please note that if you delete these cookies, we will no longer be able to remember your preferences or remember your log in details or provide you with the content you have requested. When selecting your choices for the first time, we may ask you whether you want us to remember your choices and if you do this it will constitute consent of our use of cookies for these purposes. These cookies do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing purposes or remembering where you have been on the internet. If you opt out of interest based advertising, we store your opt out preference in a cookie on your device. ****

**We use cookies to personalise your experience**

We also use cookies to change the way our website behave or look in order to personalise your experience from information we infer from your behaviour on our websites or information we already know about you e.g. because you are a registered customer. These cookies may be used to tailor the services you receive from us or the content, look and feel delivered to you on subsequent sessions to our websites. For example, if you personalise webpages, or register for products or services, a cookie helps our webpage server to recall your specific information. When you next visit our website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the website features that you previously chose.  Even if you use more than one device or computer on a regular basis, we can link cookies together so you will still receive a personalised online experience. We can also personalise the information you see based on what we already know about you, so that you spend less time looking for things. So, instead of one website for all website visitors, each visitor can have a website experience which is unique to them.

**We use cookies for analytics purposes**

We also use our own cookies and/or third party cookies and other identifiers (such as web beacons) to see how you use our websites and services in order to enhance their performance and develop them according to the taste of our customers and visitors. For example, cookies may be used to: test different designs and ensure that a consistent look and feel is maintained for users of our websites; track and provide trend analysis on how our users interact with our websites; track errors and measure the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns.  We also include web beacons in our promotional email messages or newsletters to determine whether you open and act on them and whether our mailing tools are working correctly.

The data collected will generally be aggregated to provide trends and usage patterns for business analysis, site/platform improvement and performance metrics. This analysis may be performed by third parties but will be for the review and benefit of EE only.  The type of information we collect includes how many visitors visit our websites, how many customers log in, when they visited, for how long and which areas of our websites and services.  

**We use cookies for advertising purposes**

We use cookies to collect and store information about how you interact with our websites, communications and services and selected partner websites and to identify your interests so that we can provide advertising that is most relevant and useful to you. Cookies enable us to learn about what ads you see, what ads you click, and other actions you take on our sites and other sites. We do not associate your interaction with unaffiliated sites with your identity in providing you with interest-based adverts.

In addition, we may work with third party companies, known as service providers who are authorised to place third party cookies or use other technologies on our websites or in our services, applications and tools with our permission. These service providers may use these technologies to help us deliver our own content and advertising, and measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns. If you are a registered user, the information collected from our websites is not anonymous and we may use this information along with other information we know or infer about you including your preferences to tailor content, services, advertising and offers for you. The information we collect and share with third parties through these cookies does not directly identify you. You can opt out of receiving interest based advertising on our website by blocking these cookies as described in the How to refuse or opt out of cookies section . Please also read below about advertising cookies used by third parties.

**Advertising cookies used by third parties**

We do allow advertisers and other third parties to place cookies on our websites to allow them to show you adverts that are more relevant and useful to you.  However, we do not share any information with these advertisers and third parties that will directly identify you. These advertisers and other third-parties (including the ad networks, ad-serving companies, and other service providers they may use) may assume that users who interact with or click on a personalized ad or content are part of the group that the ad or content is directed towards.

You can find out more about our interest based advertising partners and opt out of their targeted advertising by visiting these websites:

  * <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/index.aspx>

  * <http://www.velti.com/privacy>

  * <http://www.videoplazza.com/privacy>

  * <http://www.247media.com/en-us/pages/optout.html>

  * <http://www.appnexus.com/platform-policy#choices>

  * [http://www.quantcast.com/privac](http://www.quantcast.com/privacy)y

  * <http://tracking.quisma.com/optout.cfs>

  * <http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/privacy/marketing-cloud-data-cloud-privacy-policy/index.html>

Please note that the above is not an exhaustive list and is updated by us from time to time. 

The types of cookies used by these third parties and how they use the information generated by them will be governed by those companies’ privacy policies.

**Other similar technologies**

In addition to standard cookies and web beacons, our services may use other similar technologies to store and read data files from your computer. This includes the use of flash cookies which are created by Adobe Flash.  To manage these cookies, visit the Website Storage Settings Panel on www.adobe.com.  We are minimising our use of flash cookies but they may be used by third parties on our websites and services. 

**Session cookies and persistent cookies**

Our servers use two different types of cookies.

The first type is known as a 'session-based' cookie and is allocated to your computer only for the duration of your visit to our Web site. It helps you to move around the Web site faster and, if you're a registered customer, it allows us to give you information relevant to your selected service. This cookie automatically expires when you close down your browser.

The second type of cookie is known as a 'persistent' cookie. These cookies will remain on your computer for a period of time set for each cookie. These cookies allow us to:

  * limit how often you see a particular advertisement or announcement on our web site;

  * identify your preferences when customising content for you;

  * provide you with relevant self-help information;

  * record how many times you visit a page or advertisement;

  * limit and record how often you can vote in our polls;

  * confirm you are a registered user and save your login details when accessing certain services on our websites; and

  * collect statistics on the use of our services.

**How to refuse or opt out of cookies**

Most browsers automatically accept cookies but provide controls that allow you to block or delete them. If you wish to block cookies from your browser software, please check the browser help menu for relevant instructions. Take care to ensure that you select the correct type and version of your browser software:

Unfortunately, if you choose to decline cookies, some of the interactive features and some functionality of our websites and our services may not be available to you. We advise regular users of our websites and services to accept cookies from us.

If you want to know more about cookies, please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

For more information about interest based advertising and how to opt out, please visit [www.youronlinechoices.com/uk](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk)

**How to change your browser settings to disable cookies**

**Microsoft Internet Explorer 6, 7, 8 (Windows XP/Vista)**

1.            Select Tools from the main task bar, then Internet Options.

2.            Click the Privacy tab.

3.            Choose the settings you want.

4.            Click OK.

**Microsoft Internet Explorer 8,9 (Windows 7)**

1.            Click on the Settings cog icon (top right).

2.            Click on Internet Options.

3.            Click on Privacy and choose your options.

4.            Click Apply and then OK.

**Firefox 3.0+, 4.0+, 5.0+,6.0+**

1.            Choose Tools from the main task bar, then options.

2.            Click the privacy tab.

3.            Choose the settings you want.

4.            Click OK.

**Safari 5 & 6**

1.            Choose Safari from the main task bar, then preferences.

2.            Click on the privacy panel.

3.            Choose the settings you want.

4.            Click X to close

**Google Chrome**

1.            Click the menu icon and select Settings from the list.

2.            Click the Show the advance settings.

3.            Click Content Settings in the Privacy section.

4.            Choose the settings you want.

5.            Click X to close.

**Mobile Devices**

**iOS**

1.            From the home screen, choose Settings.

2.            Select Safari.

3.            Click Accept Cookies.

4.            Choose your preferred settings.

**Android**

1.            Start the browser application.

2.            Click the Menu button.

3.            Select the More option, then Settings.

4.            Tick or clear Accept cookies.

**Windows Phone 7**

1.            From the home screen, click on the right arrow.

2.            Scroll down to Settings.

3.            Swipe across and select Internet Explorer.

4.            Tick or clear Accept cookies.

**EE Analytics: mData**

EE uses mobile network usage data for analytics purposes. The analysis of this data is very important to us as it generates unique insights into mobile usage behaviours and population movement patterns. These can be used to help us better understand our customers’ behaviours, how our network performs and allows us to continuously improve and develop our network and products and services for our customers.  Examples of this type of analytics might include work to improve and minimise dropped calls, or analysis of our retail estate to identify the best locations to place EE retail stores to better serve our customers.  These insights are based on the behaviours of large anonymous groups of customers and are not about identifiable individuals. This means that any piece of information that might identify an individual, such as their name for example, have been removed to do this. 

We also provide insights to third parties.

The insights are based on mobile usage, network activity and customer demographic information in particular locations. However, those insights never relate to particular individuals. For example, insights provided to third parties could tell them that 24,560 people have visited location ‘A’ in a week or 45% of those at location ‘A’ were aged 25-34.

These insights are extremely useful to other organisations as they can help them make better decisions. We currently work with organisations within (but not limited to) the following sectors: Transport, Infrastructure, Retail, Advertising and Marketing.

Here are some examples of how these insights might be used:

Infrastructure planning: A location based insight might be used by an organisation to understand how a new road crossing format at Oxford Circus might change the way people move in that area and therefore what changes, if any should be made to existing infrastructure. Again, all insights shared are anonymised and aggregated and EE will never share information that could be used to identify an individual.

**Example location based insight:**

  * Of those who visited Oxford Circus at weekends, 4,250 or 16% travelled from Waterloo Station and 22% travelled to Kings Cross

  * 20% of those visiting location ‘A’ arrived by road

More effective outdoor advertising campaigns: A mobile usage based insight might be used to help advertising agencies advise their clients on which particular areas it is best for them to advertise in.

**Example mobile based insight:**

  * Large groups of customers who use Sports sites are most likely to be found in these locations (the area of a cell exhibiting high user volumes, generally an area at least 100 metres or larger in diameter).

Back to top

## 3\. Who We Share Your Personal Information With 

We may share your personal information with:

  * the EE Group (this means EE Limited, its subsidiaries and any parent undertakings as defined in the Companies Act 2006);

  * other third parties where you have given your consent to the disclosure (either to us or the third party);

  * our service providers including for the provision, distribution, delivery and marketing of our products and services, for advertising and payment services purposes.

These service providers have to follow our express instructions in respect of the use of your personal information and they must comply with appropriate security measures to protect your personal information. We may transfer your personal information to countries outside of the European Economic Area (the EEA, i.e. the 28 European Union Member States, as well as Iceland, Norway and Liechtenstein), which do not always provide the same level of data protection as the UK, for the purposes of providing you with our products and services. If we do make such a transfer, we will put a contract in place with our service providers including security obligations on them to ensure that your personal information is protected in accordance with UK standards:

  * credit reference agencies and fraud prevention agencies;

  * debt collection or debt tracing agencies;

  * insurance providers if you have purchased an insurance policy through us;

  * law enforcement agencies, regulators, courts and public authorities. This may include sharing your mobile number with the Environment Agency if you live in a flood risk area where a flood warning service is in operation (unless you have opted out of this service via the Environment Agency);

  * emergency services; and

  * our prospective or actual purchasers, sellers or partners and their advisers if we decide to sell, buy, merge or otherwise re-organise our business.

If you buy a product or service using Payforit (or other technology which allows you to buy products or services from third parties using your EE account), your contract for that service or product will be with the party selling the product or service (the “seller”) and not EE. In these circumstances, EE has agreed with the seller simply to charge the amount directly to your bill or prepay account. When choosing to pay by mobile, you are either entering your mobile number or agreeing that EE may pass your number onto the seller in order to complete the transaction. The seller will use your mobile number in accordance with its privacy policy and applicable terms and conditions.

Back to top

## 4\. Cookies and Other Similar Technologies

We use cookies, web beacons, unique identifiers and similar technologies to collect and store information (which may include your personal information) about how you interact with our websites, communications and services and selected third party websites which belong to our partner advertising networks. We may use these technologies to show you relevant adverts based upon this information, this is called interest-based advertising.

Cookies are small text files placed on your device which uniquely identify your device. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your device.

Web beacons (also known as “Pixel tags“) are small blocks of code on webpages or in our emails that allow us to read and set cookies. Web beacons are often used in connection with cookies to help operate our websites, emails and collect information about online activity.

For more information about our use of these technologies, interest-based advertising and your choices, please refer to our Cookies Policy.

**Our Cookies Policy**

We use cookies, web beacons, unique identifiers and other similar technologies (collectively "cookies") to provide our services and help collect data. We do this to understand your use of our websites, emails, mobile applications and services; improve your user experience and enable personalized features and content; optimize our advertisements and marketing; and to enable third-party advertising companies to assist us in serving ads specific to your interests across the Internet. By using our website, you consent to our use of these cookies.

Different cookies are used to perform different functions. We detail below our use of cookies. You do have choices about how cookies are used.

**Our use of cookies & similar technologies**

**We use cookies that are essential**

Some cookies are essential for us to use in order to provide you with the services you have requested.  These cookies will be used to manage the delivery of any web services requested by you and if you do not accept these cookies, the services may not be so easy to access and you may not be able to receive some services that you have requested e.g. pay for goods and services or access secure areas of our websites. These cookies do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing purposes or remembering where you have been on the internet.

**We use cookies to remember your selections**

We also use cookies to remember your selections that change the way our websites behave or look e.g. the font sizes or layout you have chosen etc. These types of cookies can also be used to deliver a specific function requested by you which is not core to the usage of the website e.g. streaming a video.  Please note that if you delete these cookies, we will no longer be able to remember your preferences or remember your log in details or provide you with the content you have requested. When selecting your choices for the first time, we may ask you whether you want us to remember your choices and if you do this it will constitute consent of our use of cookies for these purposes. These cookies do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing purposes or remembering where you have been on the internet. If you opt out of interest based advertising, we store your opt out preference in a cookie on your device. ****

**We use cookies to personalise your experience**

We also use cookies to change the way our website behave or look in order to personalise your experience from information we infer from your behaviour on our websites or information we already know about you e.g. because you are a registered customer. These cookies may be used to tailor the services you receive from us or the content, look and feel delivered to you on subsequent sessions to our websites. For example, if you personalise webpages, or register for products or services, a cookie helps our webpage server to recall your specific information. When you next visit our website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the website features that you previously chose.  Even if you use more than one device or computer on a regular basis, we can link cookies together so you will still receive a personalised online experience. We can also personalise the information you see based on what we already know about you, so that you spend less time looking for things. So, instead of one website for all website visitors, each visitor can have a website experience which is unique to them.

**We use cookies for analytics purposes**

We also use our own cookies and/or third party cookies and other identifiers (such as web beacons) to see how you use our websites and services in order to enhance their performance and develop them according to the taste of our customers and visitors. For example, cookies may be used to: test different designs and ensure that a consistent look and feel is maintained for users of our websites; track and provide trend analysis on how our users interact with our websites; track errors and measure the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns.  We also include web beacons in our promotional email messages or newsletters to determine whether you open and act on them and whether our mailing tools are working correctly.

The data collected will generally be aggregated to provide trends and usage patterns for business analysis, site/platform improvement and performance metrics. This analysis may be performed by third parties but will be for the review and benefit of EE only.  The type of information we collect includes how many visitors visit our websites, how many customers log in, when they visited, for how long and which areas of our websites and services.  

**We use cookies for advertising purposes**

We use cookies to collect and store information about how you interact with our websites, communications and services and selected partner websites and to identify your interests so that we can provide advertising that is most relevant and useful to you. Cookies enable us to learn about what ads you see, what ads you click, and other actions you take on our sites and other sites. We do not associate your interaction with unaffiliated sites with your identity in providing you with interest-based adverts.

In addition, we may work with third party companies, known as service providers who are authorised to place third party cookies or use other technologies on our websites or in our services, applications and tools with our permission. These service providers may use these technologies to help us deliver our own content and advertising, and measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns. If you are a registered user, the information collected from our websites is not anonymous and we may use this information along with other information we know or infer about you including your preferences to tailor content, services, advertising and offers for you. The information we collect and share with third parties through these cookies does not directly identify you. You can opt out of receiving interest based advertising on our website by blocking these cookies as described in the How to refuse or opt out of cookies section . Please also read below about advertising cookies used by third parties.

**Advertising cookies used by third parties**

We do allow advertisers and other third parties to place cookies on our websites to allow them to show you adverts that are more relevant and useful to you.  However, we do not share any information with these advertisers and third parties that will directly identify you. These advertisers and other third-parties (including the ad networks, ad-serving companies, and other service providers they may use) may assume that users who interact with or click on a personalized ad or content are part of the group that the ad or content is directed towards.

You can find out more about our interest based advertising partners and opt out of their targeted advertising by visiting these websites:

  * <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/index.aspx>

  * <http://www.velti.com/privacy>

  * <http://www.videoplazza.com/privacy>

  * <http://www.247media.com/en-us/pages/optout.html>

  * <http://www.appnexus.com/platform-policy#choices>

  * <http://www.quantcast.com/privacy>

  * <http://tracking.quisma.com/optout.cfs>

  * <http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/privacy/marketing-cloud-data-cloud-privacy-policy/index.html>

Please note that the above is not an exhaustive list and is updated by us from time to time. 

The types of cookies used by these third parties and how they use the information generated by them will be governed by those companies’ privacy policies.

**Other similar technologies**

In addition to standard cookies and web beacons, our services may use other similar technologies to store and read data files from your computer. This includes the use of flash cookies which are created by Adobe Flash.  To manage these cookies, visit the Website Storage Settings Panel on www.adobe.com.  We are minimising our use of flash cookies but they may be used by third parties on our websites and services. 

**Session cookies and persistent cookies**

Our servers use two different types of cookies.

The first type is known as a 'session-based' cookie and is allocated to your computer only for the duration of your visit to our Web site. It helps you to move around the Web site faster and, if you're a registered customer, it allows us to give you information relevant to your selected service. This cookie automatically expires when you close down your browser.

The second type of cookie is known as a 'persistent' cookie. These cookies will remain on your computer for a period of time set for each cookie. These cookies allow us to:

  * limit how often you see a particular advertisement or announcement on our web site;

  * identify your preferences when customising content for you;

  * provide you with relevant self-help information;

  * record how many times you visit a page or advertisement;

  * limit and record how often you can vote in our polls;

  * confirm you are a registered user and save your login details when accessing certain services on our websites; and

  * collect statistics on the use of our services.

**How to refuse or opt out of cookies**

Most browsers automatically accept cookies but provide controls that allow you to block or delete them. If you wish to block cookies from your browser software, please check the browser help menu for relevant instructions. Take care to ensure that you select the correct type and version of your browser software:

Unfortunately, if you choose to decline cookies, some of the interactive features and some functionality of our websites and our services may not be available to you. We advise regular users of our websites and services to accept cookies from us.

If you want to know more about cookies, please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

For more information about interest based advertising and how to opt out, please visit [www.youronlinechoices.com/uk](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk)

**How to change your browser settings to disable cookies**

**Microsoft Internet Explorer 6, 7, 8 (Windows XP/Vista)**

1.            Select Tools from the main task bar, then Internet Options.

2.            Click the Privacy tab.

3.            Choose the settings you want.

4.            Click OK.

**Microsoft Internet Explorer 8,9 (Windows 7)**

1.            Click on the Settings cog icon (top right).

2.            Click on Internet Options.

3.            Click on Privacy and choose your options.

4.            Click Apply and then OK.

**Firefox 3.0+, 4.0+, 5.0+,6.0+**

1.            Choose Tools from the main task bar, then options.

2.            Click the privacy tab.

3.            Choose the settings you want.

4.            Click OK.

**Safari 5 & 6**

1.            Choose Safari from the main task bar, then preferences.

2.            Click on the privacy panel.

3.            Choose the settings you want.

4.            Click X to close

**Google Chrome**

1.            Click the menu icon and select Settings from the list.

2.            Click the Show the advance settings.

3.            Click Content Settings in the Privacy section.

4.            Choose the settings you want.

5.            Click X to close.

**Mobile Devices**

**iOS**

1.            From the home screen, choose Settings.

2.            Select Safari.

3.            Click Accept Cookies.

4.            Choose your preferred settings.

**Android**

1.            Start the browser application.

2.            Click the Menu button.

3.            Select the More option, then Settings.

4.            Tick or clear Accept cookies.

**Windows Phone 7**

1.            From the home screen, click on the right arrow.

2.            Scroll down to Settings.

3.            Swipe across and select Internet Explorer.

4.            Tick or clear Accept cookies.

Back to top

## 5\. How Long We Keep Your Personal Information 

The periods for which we keep your information depend on the purpose for which your information was collected and the use to which it is put.  We will not keep your personal information for longer than necessary for our business purposes or for legal requirements.

Data relating to the destination, routing, timing or duration of your communications are kept for 12 months to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations (even if you stop using our services).

Some account information will be held for 6 years from the end of your contract with us.

We will keep your contact information for a reasonable period after your contract with us has finished in case you decide to use our services again and may contact you about our services during this time if you have not opted out of marketing.

Back to top

## 6\. Access and Control Your Personal Information

We want to make sure that any personal information we hold about you is up to date. So if you think your personal information is inaccurate, you can ask us to correct or remove it at no charge to you. Please contact our Customer Services team on the numbers below to do this.

Under the Data Protection Act 1998, you have a right to know what personal information we hold about you. If you'd like a copy of the information you are entitled to please write to The Disclosures Team, EE Limited, Hatfield Business Park, Hertfordshire, AL10 9BW, clearly identifying yourself and the information you require. We may charge you £10 to cover the cost of processing your request and supplying your information to you. We will ask you to provide identification to ensure we do not disclose your information to the wrong people. Please note that you can obtain copies of your phone bill free of charge on the 'My Account' section of our website.

You can always tell us that you do not wish to receive direct marketing communications from EE. But remember, if you do not want us to get in touch, you may miss out on valuable and exciting offers. If you would prefer not to receive direct marketing communications from us, simply let us know at any time by contacting us as below or by following the opt out instructions in the relevant communication. Please note that this will not stop you from receiving service messages from us.

Please call Customer Services on 150 from an EE or T-Mobile or Orange handset or 07953 966250 or 0845 412 5150 from any other phone if you wish to opt out of marketing communications. If you are a broadband customer, please call Customer services on 150 from an EE handset or 0800 079 8586 from any other phone.

Please note that it may take up to 96 hours to process your opt out request.

You can also make choices about the cookies and targeted advertising. For more information about this, please refer to our section on cookies.

**Our Cookies Policy**

We use cookies, web beacons, unique identifiers and other similar technologies (collectively "cookies") to provide our services and help collect data. We do this to understand your use of our websites, emails, mobile applications and services; improve your user experience and enable personalized features and content; optimize our advertisements and marketing; and to enable third-party advertising companies to assist us in serving ads specific to your interests across the Internet. By using our website, you consent to our use of these cookies.

Different cookies are used to perform different functions. We detail below our use of cookies. You do have choices about how cookies are used.

**Our use of cookies & similar technologies**

**We use cookies that are essential**

Some cookies are essential for us to use in order to provide you with the services you have requested.  These cookies will be used to manage the delivery of any web services requested by you and if you do not accept these cookies, the services may not be so easy to access and you may not be able to receive some services that you have requested e.g. pay for goods and services or access secure areas of our websites. These cookies do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing purposes or remembering where you have been on the internet.

**We use cookies to remember your selections**

We also use cookies to remember your selections that change the way our websites behave or look e.g. the font sizes or layout you have chosen etc. These types of cookies can also be used to deliver a specific function requested by you which is not core to the usage of the website e.g. streaming a video.  Please note that if you delete these cookies, we will no longer be able to remember your preferences or remember your log in details or provide you with the content you have requested. When selecting your choices for the first time, we may ask you whether you want us to remember your choices and if you do this it will constitute consent of our use of cookies for these purposes. These cookies do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing purposes or remembering where you have been on the internet. If you opt out of interest based advertising, we store your opt out preference in a cookie on your device. ****

**We use cookies to personalise your experience**

We also use cookies to change the way our website behave or look in order to personalise your experience from information we infer from your behaviour on our websites or information we already know about you e.g. because you are a registered customer. These cookies may be used to tailor the services you receive from us or the content, look and feel delivered to you on subsequent sessions to our websites. For example, if you personalise webpages, or register for products or services, a cookie helps our webpage server to recall your specific information. When you next visit our website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the website features that you previously chose.  Even if you use more than one device or computer on a regular basis, we can link cookies together so you will still receive a personalised online experience. We can also personalise the information you see based on what we already know about you, so that you spend less time looking for things. So, instead of one website for all website visitors, each visitor can have a website experience which is unique to them.

**We use cookies for analytics purposes**

We also use our own cookies and/or third party cookies and other identifiers (such as web beacons) to see how you use our websites and services in order to enhance their performance and develop them according to the taste of our customers and visitors. For example, cookies may be used to: test different designs and ensure that a consistent look and feel is maintained for users of our websites; track and provide trend analysis on how our users interact with our websites; track errors and measure the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns.  We also include web beacons in our promotional email messages or newsletters to determine whether you open and act on them and whether our mailing tools are working correctly.

The data collected will generally be aggregated to provide trends and usage patterns for business analysis, site/platform improvement and performance metrics. This analysis may be performed by third parties but will be for the review and benefit of EE only.  The type of information we collect includes how many visitors visit our websites, how many customers log in, when they visited, for how long and which areas of our websites and services.  

**We use cookies for advertising purposes**

We use cookies to collect and store information about how you interact with our websites, communications and services and selected partner websites and to identify your interests so that we can provide advertising that is most relevant and useful to you. Cookies enable us to learn about what ads you see, what ads you click, and other actions you take on our sites and other sites. We do not associate your interaction with unaffiliated sites with your identity in providing you with interest-based adverts.

In addition, we may work with third party companies, known as service providers who are authorised to place third party cookies or use other technologies on our websites or in our services, applications and tools with our permission. These service providers may use these technologies to help us deliver our own content and advertising, and measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns. If you are a registered user, the information collected from our websites is not anonymous and we may use this information along with other information we know or infer about you including your preferences to tailor content, services, advertising and offers for you. The information we collect and share with third parties through these cookies does not directly identify you. You can opt out of receiving interest based advertising on our website by blocking these cookies as described in the How to refuse or opt out of cookies section . Please also read below about advertising cookies used by third parties.

**Advertising cookies used by third parties**

We do allow advertisers and other third parties to place cookies on our websites to allow them to show you adverts that are more relevant and useful to you.  However, we do not share any information with these advertisers and third parties that will directly identify you. These advertisers and other third-parties (including the ad networks, ad-serving companies, and other service providers they may use) may assume that users who interact with or click on a personalized ad or content are part of the group that the ad or content is directed towards.

You can find out more about our interest based advertising partners and opt out of their targeted advertising by visiting these websites:

  * <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/index.aspx>

  * <http://www.velti.com/privacy>

  * <http://www.videoplazza.com/privacy>

  * <http://www.247media.com/en-us/pages/optout.html>

  * <http://www.appnexus.com/platform-policy#choices>

  * <http://www.quantcast.com/privacy>

  * <http://tracking.quisma.com/optout.cfs>

  * <http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/privacy/marketing-cloud-data-cloud-privacy-policy/index.html>

Please note that the above is not an exhaustive list and is updated by us from time to time. 

The types of cookies used by these third parties and how they use the information generated by them will be governed by those companies’ privacy policies.

**Other similar technologies**

In addition to standard cookies and web beacons, our services may use other similar technologies to store and read data files from your computer. This includes the use of flash cookies which are created by Adobe Flash.  To manage these cookies, visit the Website Storage Settings Panel on www.adobe.com.  We are minimising our use of flash cookies but they may be used by third parties on our websites and services. 

**Session cookies and persistent cookies**

Our servers use two different types of cookies.

The first type is known as a 'session-based' cookie and is allocated to your computer only for the duration of your visit to our Web site. It helps you to move around the Web site faster and, if you're a registered customer, it allows us to give you information relevant to your selected service. This cookie automatically expires when you close down your browser.

The second type of cookie is known as a 'persistent' cookie. These cookies will remain on your computer for a period of time set for each cookie. These cookies allow us to:

  * limit how often you see a particular advertisement or announcement on our web site;

  * identify your preferences when customising content for you;

  * provide you with relevant self-help information;

  * record how many times you visit a page or advertisement;

  * limit and record how often you can vote in our polls;

  * confirm you are a registered user and save your login details when accessing certain services on our websites; and

  * collect statistics on the use of our services.

**How to refuse or opt out of cookies**

Most browsers automatically accept cookies but provide controls that allow you to block or delete them. If you wish to block cookies from your browser software, please check the browser help menu for relevant instructions. Take care to ensure that you select the correct type and version of your browser software:

Unfortunately, if you choose to decline cookies, some of the interactive features and some functionality of our websites and our services may not be available to you. We advise regular users of our websites and services to accept cookies from us.

If you want to know more about cookies, please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

For more information about interest based advertising and how to opt out, please visit [www.youronlinechoices.com/uk](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk)

**How to change your browser settings to disable cookies**

**Microsoft Internet Explorer 6, 7, 8 (Windows XP/Vista)**

1.            Select Tools from the main task bar, then Internet Options.

2.            Click the Privacy tab.

3.            Choose the settings you want.

4.            Click OK.

**Microsoft Internet Explorer 8,9 (Windows 7)**

1.            Click on the Settings cog icon (top right).

2.            Click on Internet Options.

3.            Click on Privacy and choose your options.

4.            Click Apply and then OK.

**Firefox 3.0+, 4.0+, 5.0+,6.0+**

1.            Choose Tools from the main task bar, then options.

2.            Click the privacy tab.

3.            Choose the settings you want.

4.            Click OK.

**Safari 5 & 6**

1.            Choose Safari from the main task bar, then preferences.

2.            Click on the privacy panel.

3.            Choose the settings you want.

4.            Click X to close

**Google Chrome**

1.            Click the menu icon and select Settings from the list.

2.            Click the Show the advance settings.

3.            Click Content Settings in the Privacy section.

4.            Choose the settings you want.

5.            Click X to close.

**Mobile Devices**

**iOS**

1.            From the home screen, choose Settings.

2.            Select Safari.

3.            Click Accept Cookies.

4.            Choose your preferred settings.

**Android**

1.            Start the browser application.

2.            Click the Menu button.

3.            Select the More option, then Settings.

4.            Tick or clear Accept cookies.

**Windows Phone 7**

1.            From the home screen, click on the right arrow.

2.            Scroll down to Settings.

3.            Swipe across and select Internet Explorer.

4.            Tick or clear Accept cookies.

Back to top

## 7\. How We Protect Your Personal Information

We maintain the highest standards of data privacy and security to protect your personal details and other information about your account because we want you to feel completely confident about using our services. We regularly review our processes and procedures to protect your personal information from unauthorised access and use, accidental loss and/or destruction.

We may monitor or record any conversations between you and our staff for authentication, security, quality and training purposes.

Sometimes we use other organisations to process your personal information on our behalf. We don’t allow them to use this information for their own commercial purposes and they have to follow our strict instructions and comply with appropriate security measures. We assess the security measures in these organisations when we bring them on board and we continue to monitor their compliance while they process your personal information.

We store all your account details and other such information on secure servers, adhering to all relevant UK legislation. We use encrypted transmission links whenever we can.

For further information on how you can help us to protect your personal information, please refer to our section on accessing and controlling your personal information.

**How you can help us to protect your personal information**

**Contacting us by email or phone**

We recommend you set up a Customer Services password to protect your account details. If you don't already have one it's simple to set one up next time you call. Your password can be used to access your account so you must ensure it is something known only to you and no one else knows it.  This is to prevent someone changing your account details or taking over your account. 

If we need to call you for any reason we will not ask you to reveal your full password to us.

**Reviewing your account online**

You will need to set up a separate username and password to access your account details online. Ensure you set a password that is unique and strong and isn’t one you use for other online accounts.

**Spoof websites and email security alerts**

Fraudsters create authentic looking, but false or “spoof” websites. Their purpose is to tempt users to divulge personal information. This information will be re-used to try and access your bank accounts. Fraudsters are increasingly turning to email to generate traffic to these websites.

If you get any email containing an embedded link and a request for you to enter any personal details, treat it as suspicious and do not provide any of your personal information, even if the page appears legitimate. No reputable company ever sends emails of this type.

**Identity fraud**

If you believe you may have fallen victim to identity fraud or impersonation, CIFAS (the UK’s Fraud Prevention Service) advises you take the following steps:

  * Obtain a copy of your credit file from the credit reference agencies (see the CIFAS Website at [www.identityfraud.org.uk](http://www.identityfraud.org.uk/)  Advice for Victims for further details).

  * Contact everyone involved immediately and keep a record of all of your actions (who you spoke to and when, copies of letters sent and received etc.).

  * Immediately report the incident to the police, especially if it involves stolen identification documents. Insist on receiving a Crime Reference Number or some documentation to record the incident.

  * If a passport or driving licence is stolen or lost it should be reported to the authorities as soon as the loss is known. Also report any suspicious circumstances.

  * Immediately report all stolen cheques or cards to the issuers, and request new ones. Follow up telephone calls with written notification. Get new cards, account numbers and PINs if you use credit or other plastic cards to access banking services. Don't continue to use a compromised PIN.

  * Notify Royal Mail immediately if you suspect mail theft or suspect a mail redirection has been fraudulently set-up on your address - they have an investigations unit who will be able to help.

If you believe you may have fallen victim (i.e. you have received a bill for an account or additional number which fraudulently uses your details), you should contact us as soon as possible.

**Staying Safe Online**

For hints and tips on Staying Safe Online, please visit our website.

Back to top

## 8\. Other Important Privacy Information

**Directory enquiries**

You can ask us to include your contact details including your mobile phone number in a directory which will make your details available through directory enquiry services. Please contact our [_Customer Services Team_  ](http://ee.co.uk/help/contact-us)if you wish to do this.

**Links to third party websites**

This privacy policy does not apply to third party websites which our websites link to or which advertise on our websites. These third party websites operate their own privacy policy which we encourage you to read.

**Changes to our privacy policy**

Any changes to our privacy policy will be posted on our websites and, where appropriate notified to you by SMS or email. Changes are effective when they are posted and by continuing to use our products and services you acknowledge and agree to those changes.

**How to Contact Us**

EE Limited is the controller of your personal data and is registered as a data controller with the Information Commissioner’s Office (registration number Z7510687).

If you have any questions about our practices or this this policy, please get in touch with our _[Customer Services Team](http://ee.co.uk/help/contact-us)_.

Back to top
